准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
驾校交换生
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
裤头村
泡芙老师  我该打转向灯吗
Mrs. Puff, should I be using my blinker?
裤头村
农贸市场
蛋白质奶昔
九十八  九十九
Ninety-eight, 99
滑浪学校
要是能找到办法
If only I could find a way
把海绵宝宝给甩掉就好了
to get SpongeBob out of my hair
让海绵宝宝别碰我头发
你刚有说话吗  泡芙老师
Did you say something, Mrs. Puff?
没  海绵宝宝
Nothing, SpongeBob
我表现比昨天好多了吗  泡芙老师
I did way better than yesterday, didn't I, Mrs. Puff?
昨天
Yesterday
这是什么
What's this?
外国驾校交换生计划
"Foreign Student Driver Exchange Program"
交换生计划吗
Exchange program?
正是摆脱海绵宝宝的大好机会
This is my chance to be rid of SpongeBob
你刚说什么  泡芙老师
What was that, Mrs. Puff?
我只是很欣赏这大好机会
I was just admiring this amazing opportunity
是什么机会呢
What's the opportunity?
驾校交换生计划
A student driver exchange program
要用学生来交换什么东西呢
What do you exchange the student for?
一个学生会从一个遥远的神奇国度
A student from a faraway magical country
叫做可乐那
called Klopnod
可乐那
过来这里学习我们的驾驶方式
comes here to learn our way of driving
神奇国度可乐那
Magical country of Klopnod?
而且可神了
It's amazing
只要找个同学派过去就行了
I just have to find a student to send there
要热爱乐趣的同学
Someone that loves fun
我热爱乐趣
I love fun
要追求冒险的同学
A student that lives for adventure
我追求冒险
I live for adventure
而且还是最渴望学开船的同学
A student that wants to learn
how to drive more than anything
我最渴望学的就是开船
I want to learn how to drive more than anything
真是莫大的荣幸
It's such a big honor
只是不知道要派谁过去
I just don't know who to send
选我
Pick me
我
Me
我要乐趣  冒险
I want fun, adventure
还要学习
and learning
拜托选我吧
Please pick me
如果那对你意义这么重大  海绵宝宝
Well, if it means that much to you, SpongeBob
那你就去吧
you can go
谢谢泡芙老师
Thank you, Mrs. Puff
我等不及了
I can't wait
我也等不及
Neither can I
这是你的介绍信
Here's your introduction letter
滑浪学校
裤头村
酷乐湖
石头滩
无人区
可乐那
欢迎来到
我的介绍信沾满了泥巴
I got mud all over my introduction letter
你一定就是交换生海绵宝宝了
You must be exchange student SpongeBob
是  是的老师
Y-yes, sir
大多数同学都不知道
Most student not know
可乐那族泥巴欢迎仪式
the Klopnodian Mud greeting
你准备好学开船了吗
You ready for to learn how to drive?
我准备好了
I'm ready
海绵宝宝
学员档案
你好
Hello
你一定就是我的
You must be my
交换生胡椒子
exchange student, Peppercorn
你只会可乐那语
You only speak Klopnodian
希望这语言障碍不会影响我的教学
I hope this language barrier
doesn't impact my teaching
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
准备好见你的同学们了吗
Ready for meeting your fellow students?
我随时都准备好要见其他驾驶爱好者
I'm always ready to meet other driving enthusiasts
同学们
Students
同学们  这位是海绵宝宝
Everyone, this SpongeBob
他是裤头村来的外国交换生
He is foreign exchange student from Bikini Bottom
不好意思  教练老师
Excuse me, Mr. Driving Instructor, sir
这些貌似都是家畜
but these look like farm animals
无意冒犯
No offense
可乐那只允许动物驾驶
In Klopnod, only animals allowed to drive
那样大家才会比较安全
It's safer for everyone that way
好迷人的文化
What a fascinating culture
聊够了
Enough making talk
开始学吧
Let's get learning
好耶
Oh yeah
击掌
High five
正式开始驾驶之前
Before we getting to driving
先回顾一下交通规则
we go over rules of road
规则1
Rule 1:
第一次上路如果看见自己的影子
If you are seeing your shadow when you first enter road
就回船库两周
go back to garage for two weeks
规则2
Rule 2:
水母永远优先通行
Jellyfish always have right of way
每月奇数天除外
except on odd days of the month
泡芙老师从来没教过我这些
Mrs. Puff never taught me any of this stuff
好了  胡椒子
Alright, Peppercorn
是时候要上路了
Time to get behind the wheel
让我来评测你的驾驶技能
so I can assess your driving skills
还是比海绵宝宝强
Still better than SpongeBob
来学习第一课
Let's start with lesson one, shall we?
先检查后视镜
First, check your mirrors
今天一定会很难熬
This is going to be a long day
出口
裤头村
现在慢下来
Now slow down
好
Good
检查盲区  打转向信号
Check your blind spot, use your turn signal
从人行道汇入主路
and merge from the walkway into the street
你做到了
You did it
胡椒子  你开得完美无瑕
Peppercorn, your driving is flawless
你完全可以上高速了
I think you're ready for freeway driving
以上就是所有规则
And that is all of rules
现在来开船
Now for to make with the driving
好耶
Oh boy
发动机在哪
Where's the engine?
同学们轮流当发动机
Students take turns being engine
冷静  海绵宝宝
Keep calm, SpongeBob
你在老家通常都是开船这步搞砸了
Driving is the part you usually mess up back home
好  没看见我的影子
Okay, no sign of my shadow
开
Go
开了
Going
在开了
I'm going
我又挂了
I've failed again
我永远也学不会开船
I'll never learn how to drive
什么
What?
你疯了吗
You crazy?
你是我见过最厉害的司机
You greatest driver I ever see
真  真的吗
R-really?
看
Look
这边所有人开船都像我一样
Everyone here drives like me
给
Here
这是你应得的
You've earned this
一颗芜菁
A turnip
对
Yes
不要吃
Don't eat
看背面
Read other side
可乐那官方驾照
"Official Klopnod Driving License
持照人  海绵宝宝
issued to SpongeBob SquarePants"
快走吧
Now go
胡椒子  我怀着无比的自豪
Peppercorn, with great pride
为你颁发裤头村驾照
I present you with a Bikini Bottom Driver's License
我真为你自豪
I'm so proud of you
虽然你得回可乐那
I know you have to go back to Klopnod
但别忘了
but remember
你在裤头村永远有个朋友
you always have a friend in Bikini Bottom
我的尖子生就这么走了
There goes the best student
能教她是我莫大的荣幸
I've ever had the honor to teach
胡椒子
Peppercorn?
泡芙老师好  我回来了
Hi, Mrs. Puff, I'm back
海绵宝宝好
Hello, SpongeBob
你这么快就被踢出驾校了吗
They kick you out of driving school already?
不对  我毕业了
No, I graduated
可乐那驾照
A Klopnodian Driving License?
难道你过了
You passed?
怎么会
How?
我应该只是需要换个环境吧
Guess I just needed a change of scenery
让我来给你展示
Allow me to show you
我新学到的可乐那持照驾驶技能吧
my new Klopnodian licensed driving skills?
不得不说  我很好奇
Well, I have to say, I am curious
两分钟后
你觉得我这可乐那族驾驶技能怎么样
What do you think of my Klopnodian driving skills?
根本就跟裤头村不适配
They don't translate to Bikini Bottom
前方火山峡谷
海绵宝宝  就快冲向火山峡谷了
SpongeBob, we're headed for Volcano Gorge
打方向盘啊
Turn the wheel
我在打了
I'm turning
完蛋了
We're doomed
泡芙老师  快看
Mrs. Puff, look
是胡椒子
Peppercorn
我们得救了
We're saved
看来我还没准备好在裤头村开船
I guess I'm not ready for driving
in Bikini Bottom just yet
给  胡椒子
Here, Peppercorn
你比我更配得上这个驾照
you deserve this license more than I do
看来我明天一大早就要来上课见你了
Looks like I'll be seeing you
bright and early for class tomorrow
恐堡王
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
早安  主人
Good morning, Master
主人现在该来安稳睡个懒觉了
Time for Master to sleep tight
and bite the bedbugs good night
我带来了你最爱的睡前茶点
I brought your favorite bedtime tea
血橙汁
Blood Orange
不加橙汁
Hold the Orange
我真苦
Woe is me
主人
Master
真对不起
I'm so sorry
我被
I'm
开除了
fired?
求你了  主人
Please, Master
求你原谅我
I beg your forgiveness
看来这都是我应得的
I suppose I deserve this
几小时后
嗨  史赖皮
Hi, Slappy
你在里面干嘛
what're you doing in there?
等着收垃圾的过来
Waiting for the waste man
妥善处理我凋零又毫无价值的灵魂
to properly dispose of my withering, worthless soul
你才没凋零呢
You're not withering
你是我朋友
You're my friend
没有主人  我迷失了方向
Without a master, I am lost
我要打磨谁的棺材
Whose coffin do I polish?
我要削尖谁的尖牙
Whose fangs do I sharpen?
我需要伺候别人
I need to serve somebody
任何人都行
Anybody
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
别磨蹭了  回去工作
Quit your lollygagging and get back to work
客人又不会自己服务自己
Those customers won't serve themselves
客人也太多了吧
That is a lotta customers
看来今天得找帮手了  蟹老板
It looks like we could use some help today, Mr. Krabs
帮手
Help?
我乐意为你效劳  主人老板
I'd love to be at your service, Mister Master
你吗
You?
抱歉  我没钱再另外雇佣劳力了
Sorry, I can't afford to pay another hand
我的旧主人付我昆虫当报酬
My old master paid me in insects
灭虫人员兼服务生吗
An exterminator and a server?
简直是买一送一
That's a two-for-one deal
你被录用了
You're hired
让我帮你保管外套吧
Allow me to take your coat?
谢谢
Thank you
不对
No
应该是我谢谢你  好先生
thank you, good sir
这才是蟹堡王里值得给小费的服务
Now that's the tip-worthy service this place needs
继续努力
Keep it up
能帮你保管外套吗
May I take your coat?
可我没穿
But I'm not wearing a--
用餐愉快
Enjoy your meal
谢了
Thanks
这家伙是蟹老板雇过最可怕的怪人了
This guy is the creepiest weirdo
Mr. Krabs has ever hired
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
我认错
I stand corrected
准备好了吗  弗雷迪先生
Are you ready, Mr. Freddy?
你的新鲜食物等着你呢
Your fresh food awaits you
好哦
Oh my
的腿
leg
吓跑客人是吧
Scaring away the customers?
蟹老板一定会爱上的
Mr. Krabs is gonna love this
史赖皮  目前为止干得不错
Hey, Slappy, great work so far
客人们都很喜欢你
The customers love ya
大多是吧
Mostly
但还是别给客人吃太不寻常的东西了
But let's not feed the customers anything too unusual
像是客人自己的腿
like their own leg
说得好
Good point
胳膊大概会更多汁
Arms can be so much juicer
不如给客人端上他们点的食物
How about serving our customers what they ordered
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patties
这点子真新奇
That's a novel idea
不错
Great
真高兴能达成共识
Glad we're on the same page
欢迎  女士
Welcome, madame
不得不说
I must say
你的燕尾服真是领班级的美妙
your tuxedo is maître-d'-lightful
谢谢
Thank you
这是我被埋葬时穿的
It's the suit I was buried in
天啊
Oh my
像你这样高雅的女士
A sophisticated lady like yourself
应该坐在全餐厅最好的位置
deserves the best seat in the house
放我下来
Put me down
要来先吃个史赖皮开胃蟹黄堡吗
May I start you off with a Slappy-tizing Krabby Patty?
不要
No
拜托不要
Please no
拜托就要
Please, I insist
我还帮你嚼过了呢
I'll even chew it for you
蟹堡王
冒犯到我了
I am offended
我这位领头服务生接下来要服务谁呢
Okay, as head waiter, who can I help next?
外面干嘛在尖叫
What's with all the screaming out here?
史赖皮先生
Mr. Slappy
你把我蟹堡王的老主顾都吓跑了
You're creepin' away all me loyal Krustomers
没事的  史赖皮
Don't worry, Slappy
蟹老板对犯错还是很宽容的
Mr. Krabs is very tolerant of mistakes
你一定可以
I'm sure you can--
你被开除了
You're fired
这都是我应得的  主人老板
I deserve this, Mister Master
我无法再接受
I can no longer accept
你为我糟糕的服务支付的丰厚报酬
your generous payment for my terrible service
不过很可惜
It is a shame though
我邀请了很多朋友来这用餐
I've invited lots of friends to eat here
由我为他们服务
so I could serve them
很多朋友是吧
Lots of friends, eh?
那你这么多朋友什么时候要过来
So when would these "lots of friends" be comin' aboard?
天黑之后
After dark
好
Okay
你被录用回来了
You're unfired
暂时是这样
For now
我最好动作快点
I had better hurry
整修一下这里  迎接他们到来
and fix this place up for them
一份科学怪堡  给科学怪鱼主人
One Franken-patty for Master Frankenfish
能麻烦你一下吗
Would you do the honors?
它活过来了
It's alive
好吃的堡
Patty good
一根备用骨头  给狼人先
A spare for Mister Were
生
wolf
用骨愉快
Bone appétit
给隐形鱼的是
And for The Invisible Fish
隐形菜
an invisible dish
交给我
I'm on it
不加隐形蛋黄酱
Hold the invisible mayo
只能重做了
Now I have to start over
怪物
Monsters
史赖皮小子
Slappy-lad
你这是什么意
What is the meaning of
思
this?
你要让我发大财了
You're making me rich
继续干
Keep it up
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
救救我
Help me
高兴点  章鱼哥先生
Cheer up, Mr. Squidward
怪物钱还是钱
Monster money is still money
大家听我说个好消息
Good news, everybody
你们所有丑八怪  还有你们的钱
All you hideous beasts, and your money
随时都欢迎光临蟹堡王
are welcome at the Krusty Krab anytime
诺斯费拉图
Nosferatu?
我的旧主人
My old master?
你样子不太好啊
You don't look too good
你说什么  主人
What's that you say, Master?
我一走  就没人帮你理头发
Without me, you have nobody to cut your hair
削尖尖牙  让你保持黑白配色吗
sharpen your fangs, or keep you in black and white?
你
You
需要我吗
need me?
你都不知道
You don't know
我好久都想听你嘶嘶地说出这些话了
how long I've wanted to hear you hiss those words
我爱你  主人
I love you, Master
我爱你
I love you
我爱你  主
I love you, Mast--
继续工作  小子
Back to work boy-o
当然了  主人
Of course, Master
我愿意回来做你的小奴才
I would love to come back and be your lowly minion
不要
No
史赖皮
Slappy
别丢下我啊
Don't leave me
你应该做我的小奴才才对
You were supposed to be my lowly minion
生气的村民
Angry villagers?
对  我们很生气
Yes, we are angry
但也还很饿
But we're also hungry
对
Yeah
又气又饿的村民吗
Hangry villagers, eh?
还更好了
Even better
这边请  无法无天的暴民
Right this way, unruly mob
这就给大家凑点吃的来
We'll scare up some food for ya
蟹黄堡最能团结大家了
Nothing brings everyone together
like Krabby Patties
甚至能团结生气的村民和他们的宿敌
Even angry villagers and their mortal enemies
怪物
monsters
那些是怪物吗
Are those monsters?
抓住它们
Get them
算了
Oh well
我还是赚到了怪物的钱
I still have the monster money
原来怪物的钱是虫子
Monster money is bugs